# **TOMOYUKI KASHIRO**

### Front-end Engineer

Birth Date 30 / 04 / 1985

Languages Japanese(native), English(conversational)

Nationality Japan

Website <a href="http://tomoyukikashiro.me">http://tomoyukikashiro.me</a>

Github <u>https://github.com/kashiro</u>

Email <u>ksrtmyk@gmail.com</u>

# **Summary**

I am a front-end engineer developing website and web applications for six years.

I am learning back-end programs such as Ruby (Rails) currently. In addition to development work, I have extensive experience in managing projects as a project manager.

# **Experience**

2008 - 2010

### Java Engineer

Rakuten, Inc.

- Developed Ecommerce recommendation and ranking system utilizing Java and Perl
- Managed API application with memcached and hadoop
- Fixed bugs and maintained the site
- Managed projects with the business department

2010 - 2012

#### Front-end Engineer

Rakuten, Inc.

- Worked in front-end development using standards based on HTML5 and CSS3 working with jQuery/jQuery mobile
- Created Javascript coding guideline and reviewed codes
- Spearheaded adoption of new principles such as responsive design and mobile first
- Refined and iterated page speed by using server settings, cache server and front-end tool (minified source)

2012 - 2014

#### Front-end Engineer

KAYAC, Inc.

- Managed projects with designer and backend programmer
- Developed UI/UX with client and designer via prototyping (bootstrap, paper prototype)
- Developed project goal and its tactics with client (UI/UX and Measurement)
- Developed web application and campaign sites utilizing standards based on HTML5 and CSS3 and featured libraries such as AngularJS, Sencha Touch, and BackboneJS
- Spearheaded teaching of front-end web security within the team

## **Skills**

## **Development Language**

HTML5	****
CSS3	****
JavaScript	****
Ruby	****
NodeJS	***

## Framework, Library

jQuery	****
Sencha Touch	****
AngularJS	****
Sass (SCSS)	****
Jade	****
Ruby on Rails	***
Grunt / bower / Yeoman	****
karma / sinon / mocha	****

#### **Tools**

Heroku	***
GitHub	****
Google Analytics	****
Photoshop (slicing image)	****
Travis ci	***
Sketch3 app (slicing image)	

# **Education**

2004 - 2008

# Sociology

TOYO UNIVERSITY

I majored in Sociology to pursue a career as PR. However, I realized the impact of the Internet and have started to study skills such as HTML and CSS.